Armando Dorantes Bollain

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

1404-128 W. Cordova St. Vancouver BC V6B 0E6

□ 778-558-3029 | ■ bollain@gmail.com | ★ www.armandodb.com | ☑ bollain | 匝 Armando Bollain

Summary _

Highly professional team player with a passion for new tech and clean code. Interested in web development, distributed systems, and infrastructure. Looking for an opportunity to work in a challenging environment where I will be able to make meaningful contributions and continue to master my craft. Graduate of the University of British Columbia's second degree program in Computer Science after 5+ years working in the finance industry.

Skills

Programming JavaScript, C#, C, Java, Go, SQL

Operating Systems Linux, OSX, Windows

Web Rails, Node.js, Swagger, Express, React, HTML5, SASS

Languages English, Spanish

Education

University of British Columbia

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, GPA: 83%

· Co-operative Education Designation

Thompson Rivers University

BACHELOR IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

- Honours
- Major in Finance, Minor in Economics

Vancouver, British Columbia

Sept. 2014 - Dec. 2017

Kamloops, British Columbia

Sept. 2008 - Apr. 2008

May 2017 - September 2017

Work Experience_

Vision Critical Vancouver, British Columbia

RELEASE ENGINEERING CO-OP

Implemented a tool to populate secrets from Vault using a Golang script.
Member of a team working on a rewrite of several scripts from different sources to a single C# command line tool.

Vision Critical Vancouver, British Col

Vancouver, British Columbia

• Member of the development team responsible for overhauling the client-facing reporting solution for the Ideascreen application.

- Implemented new visualizations using React and Redux.
- Developed a strong understanding of the Continuous Delivery approach, working closely with testing and deployment and actively participated in weekly releases, at times leading them
- Responsible for delivering a new feature that allowed users to synch data directly from the reports. This involved the creation of new REST API endpoints, and working closely with the UX team to get the right look and feel for the new feature.

CIBC Lending & Credit

Vancouver, British Columbia

INTERMEDIATE UNDERWRITER

March 2013 - July 2014

- Responsible for underwriting residential mortgages in Western Canada with a personal lending authority of \$1.5M.
- · Consistently met & exceeded productivity goals, maintaining a high level of service with our clients and business partners.

GE Capital Vancouver, British Columbia

Underwriter September 2008 - March 2013

• Underwrote commercial credit applications of up to \$5M for companies working in the construction, forestry and oil & gas sector in Western Canada.

JANUARY 9, 2018 ARMANDO BOLLAIN · RÉSUMÉ 1



Inukshuk Class Project

Full-stack Developer Jan. 2017 - PRESENT

- Developed using React-Native with a Node.js back-end.
- Application that allows users to set up alerts before they go on hikes. If they don't return by a certain time, automated text messages are sent to the emergency contact with the last known GPS location of user.
- Responsible for back-end development main tasks included integrating SMS alerts with Twilio and implementing a REST API that was fully
 documented using Swagger.
- · Implemented back end test-suite, automated regression testing and code linting prior to pull-requests being approved.
- https://youtu.be/qVtyLHlWd1I

Ride the Buzz BCS Hackathon

DEVELOPER November 2015

• Rails app that allows users to set SMS alerts to let them know when their bus is nearing their preferred stop.

H2Go Class Project

DEVELOPER July 2015

- Web-app that maps drinking fountains and bike racks in the City of Vancouver based on a user's location.
- Allows users to create profiles to save their favourite bike racks and drinking fountains, and allows them to tweet their favourite locations.
- Developed using Ruby on Rails as part of a 5-week course in software engineering, following agile methodologies (https://h2go.herokuapp.com/)

BeerAppBCS Hackathon

DEVELOPER March 2015

- Command line application that allows users to find the perfect food pairing for their favourite brew.
- · Leverages multiple 3rd party APIs.

Extracurricular Activities

- Cycling (Strava user: Armando Bollain)
- Home-brewing
- Rock climbing (Indoors and outdoors)
- Hacking on Raspberry Pi/Linux
- · Learning iOS/Swift Development